(Yoon Chan Young)
"(يوون تشان يونغ)"
(Bong Jae Hyun)
"(بونغ جاي هيون)"
(Special Appearance, Lee Seo Jin)
"ظهور خاص (لي سيو جين)"
(Lee Kyoung Young, Seo Tae Hwa, Hwang Bo Ra)
"(لي كيونغ يونغ)، (سيو تاي هوا)، (هوانغ بو را)"
(Lee Hee Jin, Won Tae Min, Ko Dong Wook, Joo Yoon Chan)
"(لي هي جين)، (وون تاي مين) (كو دونغ ووك)، (جوو يوون تشان)"
(High School Return of a Gangster)
"انتقام طالب"
(Incoming call)
"اتصال وارد"
It was quite a shock to get a phone call from the police...
"إن تَلَقِّي اتصالاً من الشرطة كان صادماً..."
in the morning, wasn't it?
"في الصباح الباكر، أليس كذلك؟"
Nonetheless, we should still meet.
"ومع هذا علينا الالتقاء"
Come to the parking lot.
"تعال إلى موقف السيارات"
I should have figured out...
كان عليَّ أن أكتشف...
that you were behind this...
أنك المسؤولة عن هذا...
when those punks caused this kind of trouble.
عندما تسبب هؤلاء الحمقى بهذه المشكلة
I let my guard down.
سأتخلى عن حذري
Come on. You managed to win over the guys from the Dongsoo Gang too.
لقد تمكنت من كسب القتال ضد عصابة (دونغسوو) أيضاً
So they're your uncles. Right?
إذاً، هل هم أقاربك؟
But this is too bad. I don't need your uncles anymore.
ولكن للأسف، لا أحتاج إليهم بعد الآن
I plan to get things done my way.
أخطط لتنفيذ الأمور على طريقتي
So it suits my style.
على نحو يناسب أسلوبي الخاص
We filed a complaint against him like you told us to do.
لقد قدمنا شكوى بحقه كما طلبتِ منا
We deleted all the videos from social media.
وحذفنا المقاطع المصورة جميعها من وسائل التواصل
Some kids saw us when he beat us up. So we talked them into...
بعض الأولاد شاهدوه يضربنا لذا تحدثنا إليهم...
becoming our witnesses.
كي يشهدوا لصالحنا
What about our reward?
ماذا عن جائزتنا؟
Awesome.
رائع
Hey, what are you doing? We're in front of a police station.
ماذا تفعل؟ إننا أمام مركز الشرطة
Song Yi Heon's family is loaded.
عائلة (سونغ يي هيون) لها ثقلها
I'm certain he's going to challenge us on this.
أنا متيقن أنه لن يسكت عن الأمر
You will get us a lawyer, right?
ستوكلين لنا محامياً، أليس كذلك؟
Right. You'll get us jobs too.
وستؤمنين لنا عملاً أيضاً
Have you been fooled all your life?
هل كنتم حمقى طوال حياتكم؟
Why are you guys so suspicious of everything?
لمَ تشكون في كل شيء؟
Come here.
تعال
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
As long as you help me send him to a juvenile detention centre,
طالما تساعدونني على إرساله إلى سجن الأحداث
I'll be taking care of you guys for life.
سأهتم بكم دائماً
- Gosh. - Nice.
- يا للروعة! - رائع!
Thank you!
شكراً لكِ
- Let's go. - Nice.
- لنذهب - رائع
Giving drugs to my mother wasn't enough?
إعطاء والدتي العقاقير لم يكن كافياً؟
How could you do something like this?
كيف أمكنك فعل هذا؟
Drugs?
عقاقير؟
Me?
أنا؟
Oh, my. You should double-check on that.
عليك التحقق من الأمر مجدداً
Are you sure I gave her the drugs?
هل أنت متيقن أنني مَن أعطيتها العقاقير؟
The record must say that she got them prescribed herself.
سيؤكد لك السجل أنها حصلت على وصفة لهم
Oh, my.
يا للعجب!
You're scaring me.
أنت تخيفني
Even if you're angry, you should try to hold back...
حتى إن كنت غاضباً، عليك أن تكبح نفسك...
because I didn't come here alone.
لأنني لم آتِ هنا وحيدة
You won't be able to catch me.
لن تتمكن من القبض عليّ
You can try all you want,
يمكنك المحاولة كما تريد
but you must have realized that you can't beat me. So decide.
لكن لا بد أنك أدركت أنه لا يمكنك هزيمتي، لذا قرر
Will you go abroad to study? Or will you go to juvie?
هل ستسافر إلى الدراسة؟ أم تذهب إلى سجن الأحداث؟
I see.
فهمت
You tried to abduct my mother, but you failed.
أخفقت في خطف أمي
So you want to get rid of me first?
لذا تريدين التخلص مني أولاً؟
It doesn't matter if I go abroad or juvie.
لا يهم إن كنت سأسافر أم أدخل إلى سجن الأحداث
My mother will be sent to a psychiatric institution.
ستُرسل أمي إلى المصح النفسي
Once his wife passes away and my mother is in a hospital,
حالما تموت زوجته ووالدتي ستكون في المستشفى
you must think you will become his next wife.
لذا تظنين بالتأكيد أنك زوجته التالية
Have you heard of this saying?
هل سمعتِ هذه المقولة؟
"If you try to filter out makgeolli, you'll even lose the dregs."
"إن حاولتِ تصفية مشروب الأرز ستفقدين عنصر الثمالة"
It means trying to score big...
أي إن حاولت بشدة...
can backfire and cause you to suffer a loss.
سيعود الأمر عليك بخسارة كبيرة
Enough is enough.
هذا يكفي
I want you to stop meddling in my life.
أريدك أن تتوقفي عن التدخل في حياتي
Go and tell your homeroom teacher that you're going abroad to study.
أخبر عائلتك أنك ستدرس في الخارج
If you don't do that, you'll end up in juvie.
إن لم تفعل هذا ستدخل إلى سجن الأحداث
Then you'll never be able to find your mother. Why?
عندئذ لن تسطيع إيجاد والدتك أبداً أتعلم لماذا؟
Because I'll lock her up in a place that's not even listed on the map.
لأنني سأحتجزها في مكان لم يوضع على الخريطة بعد
(High School Return of a Gangster)
"انتقام طالب"
(Episode 7)
"الحلقة السابعة"
I'm going to school.
سأذهب إلى المدرسة
Have the driver drop you off at school starting today.
أخبر السائق أن يوصلك إلى المدرسة من اليوم
Try to adjust to the changes at school.
حاول التأقلم مع التغييرات في المدرسة
These changes are taking you to the right direction.
هذه التغييرات ستدفعك في الاتجاه الصحيح
So stop acting out.
توقف عن إثارة المشكلات
It's the student government president.
"إنه رئيس الهيئة الطلابية"
He came to school today.
"جاء إلى المدرسة اليوم"
Right. I wonder if he's okay.
"صحيح، أتساءل إن كان بخير"
You're in my class as of today.
أنت في صفي بدءاً من اليوم
- What? - You got separated...
- ماذا؟ - لقد أبعدوك...
from Song Yi Heon.
عن (سونغ يي هيون)
You asked the school to do that...
أنت طلبت من الإدارة فعل هذا...
because a victim and a school bully shouldn't be in the same class.
لأنه لا يمكن لضحية ومتنمر البقاء في صف واحد
So you were moved to my class.
لذا نقلوك إلى صفي
What are you talking about? The school bully?
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟ المتنمر؟
The principal, the school violence committee,
المدير وهيئة مكافحة العنف المدرسي
and the parents' association...
وهيئة الأهالي...
decided on that before the weekend.
قرروا هذا قبل عطلة نهاية الأسبوع
Song Yi Heon was called by the school violence committee.
طُلب (سونغ يي هيون) إلى مجلس مكافحة العنف
The person you have reached is unavailable.
"الشخص المطلوب غير متاح حالياً"
You'll be directed to voicemail after the tone.
"ستُحول إلى البريد الصوتي بعد سماع الصافرة"
You will be charged then.
"وستدفع الأجور عندئذ"
- He's here. - Hey.
- إنه هنا - انظروا
Ice Cream is dead. How?
توقف إنتاج المثلجات، كيف يا ترى؟
Did it freeze to death?
هل تجمد حتى الموت؟
The more you eat this, the colder you get. What is this dish?
كلما أكلت من هذا الطبق، كلما ازددت برداً
Chili?
"تشيلي"؟
What kind of bread can you wear across your body?
ما هو نوع الخبز الذي تستطيع أن تلبسه؟
- Bag-it... Baguette. - Correct.
- الحقيبة... خبز "باغيت" - صحيح
You pass.
لقد نجحت
Are you all right?
هل أنت بخير؟
You must feel uncomfortable too.
لا بد أنكن منزعجات كذلك
You don't have to force yourselves to act like my friends.
ليس عليكن إجبار أنفسكن على معاملتي كصديقكن
Gosh.
يا للعجب!
Now that Se Kyung isn't here, you must be nicer to us...
بعد ذهاب (سي كيونغ) عليك معاملتنا على نحو ألطف...
because I'll be helping you study math.
لأنني سأساعدك على دراسة الرياضيات
I might not be as smart as Se Kyung,
لست ذكية بقدر (سي كيونغ)"
but I got a Grade One for math.
لكنني حصلت على الدرجة الأولى في الرياضيات
I'll help you study Korean and science.
سأساعدك على دراسة اللغة الكورية والعلوم
I'll go to the snack bar with you.
سأذهب إلى محل الوجبات السريعة معك
It was my idea to buy all this.
كانت فكرتي شراء كل هذا
Respect.
شكراً لكِ
Nice.
رائع
Thank you.
شكراً لكنّ
How could you be called by the school violence committee?
كيف تُطلب إلى مجلس مكافحة العنف المدرسي؟
If they had known how close you guys were,
لو علموا كم كنتما مقربين
they would've never done that.
لما فعلوا هذا أبداً
Exactly.
صحيح
When I saw Se Kyung smile while hanging out with you,
حين رأيت ابتسامة (سي كيونغ) عندما كان يتسكع معك
it made me wonder if he was the same Se Kyung I knew.
تساءلت إن كان (سي كيونغ) هو الذي أعرفه نفسه
For some reason, something about him sparkled.
توهّج بشكل غريب لسبب ما
Like that?
هكذا؟
I heard you moved to Class One. Did I hear wrong?
سمعت أنك نُقلت إلى الصف واحد هل هناك خطأ ما؟
As for the school violence committee,
فيما يخص مجلس مكافحة العنف المدرسي
the adults must've gotten the wrong idea.
لا بد أن الأهل وصلتهم الفكرة الخاطئة
I already told the principal.
أخبرت المدير بالفعل
Everything will go away soon. So don't treat us differently.
سينتهي كل شيء قريباً لذا لا تعاملانا على نحو مختلف
- Have you been well? - Yes.
- هل أنتن بخير؟ - نعم
What about you?
ماذا عنك؟
Hey, student government president.
يا رئيس الهيئة الطلابية
You look especially handsome today.
تبدو وسيماً جداً اليوم
- Come on. - Right.
- هيا - هذا صحيح
There's no way Yi Heon hit Se Kyung.
لا يمكن أن يكون (يي هيون) قد ضرب (سي كيونغ)
Yi Heon. I never doubted you.
لم أشك فيك أبداً يا (يي هيون)
Hey. What do you mean, the hearing will go away?
ماذا تعني؟ هل ستُلغى جلسة الاستماع؟
I can fill out a form to request to cancel the hearing.
يمكنني تقديم طلب بإلغاء الجلسة
The victim and the guardian have to sign the form. That's it.
فقط سيوقع على الطلب الضحية والوصي
I doubt your father will do that.
لا أظن أن والدك سيقبل
Don't worry. This happened because of me.
لا تقلق، حدث هذا بسببي
I want to fix it.
أريد إصلاح الأمر
You're all grown up now.
لقد نضجت الآن
You!
أنت!
I heard Byung Chul and Duk Jun reported you for school violence.
سمعت أن (بيونغ تشول) و(دوك جون) اشتكوا عليك لمجلس المكافحة
- What? - What?
- ماذا؟
- They reported him? - What?
- هل اشتكوا عليه؟
- Yi Heon did what? - Yi Heon did that?
- ماذا فعل (يي هيون)؟
- What did he do? - What?
- ماذا فعل؟ - ماذا؟
Apparently, I beat them up.
من الواضح أنني ضربتهم
You must have beaten them up badly if they reported you to the police.
لا بد أنك أبرحتهم ضرباً حتى أبلغوا الشرطة
Gosh. You're so dense. Do you think he really did that?
أنت حقاً أحمق، هل تظن أنه فعل هذا حقاً؟
If he didn't, why did they report him?
إن لم يفعل، لمَ اشتكوا عليه؟
I don't know why.
لا أعلم لماذا
They bullied Yi Heon. But they reported Yi Heon.
لقد تنمروا على (يي هيون) ثم اشتكوا عليه
They're probably trying to make him the school bully...
لا بد أنهم يحاولون وسمه بالمتنمر...
when he's the victim by beating him to the punch.
لأنه الضحية الذي تلقى الضرب
They're trying to send me to juvie. That's why.
إنهم يحاولون إرسالي إلى سجن الأحداث
There's a woman named Lee Mi Kyung.
هناك امرأة تدعى (لي مي كيونغ)
She's the one who ordered the gang to abduct my mother.
هي مَن طلبت من العصابة خطف أمي
She sweet-talked them into reporting me to the police.
لقد استخدمت الأسلوب اللطيف ليقدموا الشكوى
But where did you hear the news?
لكن كيف سمعت الخبر؟
Well, I happened to overhear it...
لقد سمعته مصادفة...
on my way to school.
في طريقي إلى المدرسة
So those jerks won't be coming to school today.
لهذا لن يأتي هؤلاء الحمقى إلى المدرسة اليوم
Do you now realize you had been hanging out with such dirtbags?
هل أدركت الآن أنك كنت صديقاً لحفنة حثالة؟
Darn it. Why are you taking it out on me again?
سحقاً، لماذا تغضب عليَّ مجدداً؟
You, maybes sicko.
أيها "ربما" المريض النفسي
What's "maybes?"
ماذا تعني بـ "ربما"؟
Hey, if someone bites you,
إن عضك أحدهم
you can report him for assault, right?
ستشتكي بتهمة الاعتداء، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, probably.
نعم، ربما
Hey, do you have proof?
هل لديك دليل؟
Even if I have to search all the hidden cameras in that area,
حتى إن اضطررت للبحث في أجهزة المراقبة المخفية كلها
I'll find the video for proof.
سوف أجد الدليل
Hidden cameras?
أجهزة مراقبة مخفية؟
- You must mean security cameras. - Tomato tomahto!
- لا بد أنك تعني أجهزة المراقبة الأمنية - أياً كان الأمر
Hey, stop fighting.
توقفا عن المشاجرة
So tell me. Where are Byung Chul and Duk Jun now?
وأخبراني، أين (بيونغ تشول) و(دوك جون) الآن؟
They're probably idling away at the billiard club around school.
لا بد أنهم يضيعون الوقت في صالة البلياردو بجانب المدرسة
I'll be back.
سأعود
What? Are you sure you'll be okay?
ماذا؟ هل أنت متيقن أنك ستكون بخير؟
The class found out that they reported you.
لقد عرف طلاب الصف أنهم أبلغوا عنك
So the whole school must know about it by now.
إلى الآن فالمدرسة كلها سمعت بالأمر
I've done nothing wrong. Why should I be worried?
لم أخطئ، لمَ عليَّ القلق؟
Wait. Am I responsible for making everyone find out about this?
انتظر، هل هو خطأي أن الجميع علم بالأمر؟
Because of what I said out loud earlier?
بسبب ما قلته على الملأ قبل قليل
Even if you didn't say anything,
حتى إن لم تقل شيئاً
they were bound to find out once the police came to school.
كان سيعلمون عندما تأتي الشرطة إلى المدرسة
Get back inside.
عودا إلى الداخل
The study hall will start soon.
ستبدأ حلقة الدراسة قريباً
Right? I have nothing to worry about. Right?
اسمع، لن أقلق بشأن شيء، أليس كذلك؟
You still don't understand...
ما زلت لا تفهم...
that you caused everything that's happening now. Right?
أنك تسببت بما يحدث الآن كله، هل فهمت؟
What do you mean? Why is this my fault?
ماذا تعني؟ لمَ هو خطأي؟
Ask your best friends.
اسأل أصدقاءك المقربين
They know exactly...
يعلمون تماماً...
what you've done.
ماذا فعلت؟
I know that...
أعلم...
you're not behind the recent turn of events.
أنكم لستم المسؤولين عن تحول مجرى الأمور مؤخراً
I feel bad that you're being used as disposable pawns...
يؤسفني أنكم تُستغلون كبيادق غير مهمة
in this mess, created by adults.
في هذه الفوضى المنظمة من الكبار
So let me give you one last chance.
لذا دعوني أنصحكم بشيء أخير
Withdraw your complaint and come back to school now.
اسحبوا البلاغ وتعالوا إلى المدرسة الآن
Then I won't take issue with this.
حينئذ لن أتصرف مع الأمر
You need a high school diploma to have a decent life.
عليكم الحصول على شهادة الثانوية لحياة كريمة
This is your last chance.
هذه فرصتكم الأخيرة
What? You did beat us up.
ماذا؟ لقد أبرحتنا ضرباً
If you don't drop the charges,
إن لم تتنازلوا عن البلاغ
I'll report you to the police too.
سأبلغ عنكم الشرطة أيضاً
Then we'll find out who the real school bully is.
حينئذ سيرون المتنمر الحقيقي للمدرسة
"Kihojise."
"كيهوجيسه"
(A metaphor to describe a situation when one cannot stop one's pursuit)
"عبارة مجازية تصف شخصاً لم يستطع عرقلة شخص آخر"
I'll take charge as if I were galloping on a tiger.
سأتبنى التهمة بجرأة وقوة
And once I bite, I won't let go.
وحالما أبدأ بالانتقام، لن أتوقف
If you're curious, take this matter to the end and see.
إن أردتم المعرفة، أكملوا طريقكم هذا وسترون
- That jerk. - No way.
- ذلك الأحمق - لا يمكن
- Gallop? - Guys.
- بقوة؟ - اسمعوا
Do you think you can give up the money?
هل تستطيعون التخلي عن المال؟
Are you out of your mind?
هل جُننت؟
We haven't had a big score like this in a while. How can we give it up?
لم نكسب مبلغاً كهذا منذ مدة، لمَ لنستسلم؟
Then let's get Hong Jae Min to report him to the police too.
إذاً لندع (هونغ جاي مين) يبلغ عنه الشرطة أيضاً
What?
ماذا؟
The kids we beat up will never testify against us...
الأولاد الذين نضربهم لن يشهدوا ضدنا أبداً...
because they're scared of us.
لأنهم خائفون منا
We never bullied him in the classroom.
لم نتنمر عليه في الصف قط
So the only person who knows exactly how we bullied Song Yi Heon...
لذا الشخص الوحيد الذي يعلم تماماً كيف تنمرنا على (سونغ يي هيون)...
is Hong Jae Min.
هو (هونغ جاي مين)
You're right.
أنت محق
There are no videos or witnesses.
لا يوجد مقاطع مصورة أو شهود
Even if Song Yi Heon says that we bullied him,
حتى إن تحدث (سونغ يي هيون) أننا نتنمر عليه
there's no evidence.
لا يوجد دليل
We just have to get Hong Jae Min on our side. That's it.
علينا فقط أن نكسب (هونغ جاي مين) إلى طرفنا
Yes.
نعم
Hey, call him now.
اتصل به الآن
Hey. If you do this, you might end up in big trouble.
إن فعلت هذا، ستقع في مشكلة كبيرة جداً
Haven't you heard of colony?
هل سمعت عن "المستعمرة"؟
If you try to frame an innocent person...
إن حاولت تلفيق تهمة لشخص بريء...
for a crime they didn't commit,
لجريمة لم يرتكبها
you'll be arrested for colony.
ستُعتقل بتهمة "المستعمرة"
Well, isn't it "calumny?"
أليست الكلمة المقصودة "افتراء"؟
Anyway, if you trust that lady...
لا يهم، إذا كنتم تثقون بالسيدة...
and try to send Song Yi Heon to juvie,
وحاولتم إدخال (سونغ يي هيون) إلى الأحداث
you might end up getting in trouble.
قد تقعون في مشكلة كبيرة
Hey, we have nothing to lose.
ليس لدينا ما نخسره
I don't know when it will be,
لا أعلم متى سيحصل
but when he reports us for school violence,
لكن عندما يبلغ عنا لمجلس المكافحة
we must prepare to fight back.
علينا الاستعداد للمواجهة
And that lady will help us do that.
وتلك السيدة ستساعدنا بهذا
Hey, she'll get us a lawyer too.
ستوكل لنا محامياً أيضاً
When we graduate, we'll get us jobs too.
وعندما نتخرج، ستجد لنا عملاً
Gosh. That lady sounds scary.
عجباً! تلك السيدة تبدو مخيفة
But to report him...
ولكن لكي تُبلغ عنه...
for school violence, don't you need a medical note?
إلى مجلس المكافحة ألا تحتاج إلى تقرير طبي برأيك؟
It's been ages since he hit you.
لقد مر وقت طويل على ضربه لك
Besides, you hit him too.
ثم أنك تضربه أيضاً
We already got the medical note...
لقد حصلنا على التقرير بالفعل...
when you beat us up a while ago.
عندما ضربتنا قبل مدة
- What? - Hey. If you didn't beat us up,
- ماذا؟ - لو لم تضربنا
we probably had to punch each other.
لكان أحدنا لكم الآخر على الأغلب
Hey, that's not right.
هذا ليس صحيحاً
How could you use that to report him?
كيف تستخدمونه للإبلاغ عنه؟
That's fraud.
هذا احتيال
I get that you guys love money.
أفهم أنكم تحبون المال
But don't you have a conscience, you tricksters?
ولكن ألا ضمير لديكم أيها المحتالون؟
Gosh. Talk about having double standards, Jae Min.
عجبتُ لك يا (جاي مين)، لديك ازدواجية في المعايير
You were the one who started bullying him for money.
كنت البادئ بالتنمر عليه من أجل المال
You were the one who made him bring alcohol...
أنت مَن جعلته يحضر المشروب...
because his family seemed rich.
لأن عائلته تبدو ثرية
You made him bring jewellery from his house too.
جعلته يُحضر المجوهرات من منزله أيضاً
When Song Yi Heon got scared and indeed brought the jewellery,
عندما خاف (سونغ يي هيون) وأحضر المجوهرات
you were over the moon.
كنت أسعد مخلوق
Don't you think we'll at least get 5,000 dollars?
"ألا تظن أننا سنحصل على خمسة آلاف دولار على الأقل"
No way. That's too much.
"غير ممكن، هذا كثير جداً"
Hey. If we get 5,000 dollars, the 5 of us can...
"إذا حصلنا على خمسة آلاف دولار، يمكننا..."
- We're getting 3,000 dollars? - He signalled 3,000 dollars.
- "سنحصل على ثلاثة آلاف دولار؟" - "لقد أشار أنها ثلاثة آلاف دولار"
- If we're getting 3,000 dollars... - Hey, let's divide that by...
- "إن كنا سنأخذ ثلاثة آلاف دولار..." - "لنقسم على..."
Gosh.
"يا للروعة!"
This is cool.
"هذا رائع!"
- Come here. - Hey. Over here.
- "تعال" - "يا هذا"
When he told you he didn't have any more stuff to bring,
عندما أخبرك أنه لم يعد لديه شيء لإحضاره...
you slapped him and told him to steal some.
صفعته وأخبرته أن يسرق شيئاً
That's when we started to beat him up.
حينئذ بدأنا بضربه
We locked him up, threw milk at him,
سجنّاه وسكبنا الحليب عليه
singed him. We even made him strip.
أحرقناه قليلاً، حتى إننا جعلناه يتعرّى
If I were him, I would've committed suicide a long time ago.
لو كنا في موقفه، لانتحرنا منذ وقت طويل
You bullied him for two years. How could you not remember that?
لقد تنمرت عليه لسنتين، كيف نسيت هذا؟
Exactly. If you make this mistake again,
تماماً، إن قمت بهذا الخطأ مجدداً
you'll be the school bully. Got it?
ستكون متنمر المدرسة، هل فهمت؟
Don't even think about testifying or anything like that.
لا تفكر بالشهادة وما إلى ذلك
If you do, you'll end up going to juvie.
إن فعلت هذا، ستدخل سجن الأحداث
Besides, when he reports us, your name is bound to come up.
ثم إنه عندما يُبلغ عنا سيذكر اسمك بالتأكيد
Do you think he won't name you because you didn't report him?
أتظن أنه لن يفعلها لمجرد أنك لم تبلغ عنه؟
You started this whole thing.
أنت مَن بدأ بهذا كله
We must beat him to the punch before he gets a chance.
يجب أن نضربه قبل أن تسنح له الفرصة
Let's report him together.
لنبلغ عنه معاً
We have the upper hand.
لدينا اليد الطولى
(Violent Crimes Team 2)
"قسم الجنايات الفرقة الثانية"
Wait.
انتظر
This case is unfavourable to me?
هل هذه القضية ليست في صالحي؟
Yes. They said they had witnesses who saw you beat up...
نعم، قالوا إن لديهم شهوداً خلال ضربك لهم...
Jang Byung Chul and Park Duk Jun near the garbage incinerator.
(جانغ بيونغ تشول) و(بارك دوك جون) بالقرب من محرقة النفايات
Detective, I'm the victim.
أنا الضحية هنا أيها المحقق
So you're telling me you're the victim,
إذاً تقول إنك الضحية
not the school bully?
ولست المتنمر؟
They told me that you've been bullying them...
أخبروني أنك كنت تتنمر عليهم...
since the first semester of your senior year.
منذ الفصل الأول لسنة التخرج
Song Yi Heon...
بل (سونغ يي هيون)...
I mean, I've been bullied...
أعني، أنا تعرضت للتنمر...
by them ever since I started high school.
من قبلهم منذ بداية الدراسة الثانوية
I even have a journal where I recorded how they bullied me.
لدي دفتر يوميات وثَّقت فيه تنمرهم عليّ
I can find videos of them bullying me on an online forum too.
يمكنني إيجاد مقاطع مصورة تظهر تنمرهم عليّ من منتديات على الإنترنت
Give me a second.
انتظر لحظة
(Bamboo Forest: Hansong High School)
"بامبو فوريست: ثانوية (هانسونغ)"
They must have deleted all the videos.
لا بد أنهم حذفوا المقاطع جميعها
The videos were definitely on here.
كانت المقاطع محمّلة هنا بالتأكيد
(Violent Crimes Team 1)
"قسم الجنايات الفريق الأول"
Gosh. Seriously.
عجباً، جدياً!
So your mother is in the hospital.
إذاً والدتك في المستشفى
And you can't get in touch with your father.
ولا يمكنني التواصل مع والدك
Gosh. Let's stop here for today.
لننهِ الأمر اليوم
Bring the journal...
أحضر المدونة...
where you wrote down how they bullied you...
التي كتبت فيها كيف تنمروا عليك...
or videos you just mentioned at the next questioning.
أو المقاطع التي ذكرتها الآن إلى الاستجواب التالي
Just bring anything that could be used as evidence.
أو أحضر أي شيء يُعد دليلاً
And if you can find a friend who can testify...
وإن وجدت صديقاً يمكنه أن يشهد...
that you were bullied at school,
أنك تعرضت للتنمر في المدرسة
bring that friend no matter what.
أحضره بكل تأكيد
That way, you can only prove that you're not the school bully.
هكذا تُثبت أنك لست المتنمر في المدرسة
Yes, sir.
حسناً سيدي
Shouldn't you be studying at school?
ألا ينبغي أن تكون في المدرسة؟
Should you skip school like this?
هل يمكنك التغيب هكذا؟
I shouldn't.
لا يمكنني
But I can only focus on my studies once I handle this matter.
ولكن يمكنني التركيز في دروسي إن حللت هذه المسألة
Lee Mi Kyung got my classmates to report me for school violence.
جعلت (لي مي كيونغ) زملائي يبلغون عني مجلس مكافحة العنف المدرسي
She's going to send me to juvie.
سترسلني إلى سجن الأحداث
What? Juvie? Isn't that the same as the slammer?
ماذا؟ الأحداث؟ أليس هذا ما يشبه السجن؟
Gosh. Is she out of her mind?
بئساً، هل فقدت صوابها؟
Don't tell me you've been using...
هل كنت تستخدم...
the skills your father taught you to beat up other kids.
المهارات التي تعلمتها من والدك لضرب الأولاد
Did you beat them to a pulp?
هل تماديت في ضربهم؟
No, I got beaten up.
لا، بل أنا مَن ضُرب
Who is this jerk that beat you up?
مَن هو النذل الذي ضربك؟
How dare he come after my dear nephew?
مَن يمكنه إلحاق الأذى بابن أخي العزيز؟
Let's go and crush this jerk.
لنذهب ونسحق ذلك الأحمق
Let's go.
لنذهب
But I ended up getting framed as the school bully.
ولكن لُفقت لي تهمة المتنمر في المدرسة
I was called by the school violence committee too.
وطلبني مجلس مكافحة العنف المدرسي أيضاً
- Then... - What...
- إذاً... - ماذا...
What is this about?
ما الأمر؟
They're claiming that I beat them up.
يزعمون أنني ضربتهم
What?
ماذا؟
Gosh.
عجباً
I talked to my classmates, so they would come to their senses.
تحدثت إلى زملائي كي يعودوا إلى صوابهم
If they still don't withdraw their complaint,
إن لم يسحبوا الشكوى
we must get Lee Mi Kyung, so she makes them drop the charges.
علينا الضغط على (لي مي كيونغ) لتجعلهم يتراجعون
Besides, we must get Lee Mi Kyung no matter what...
بل علينا النيل منها بالأحوال كلها...
because there's no guarantee...
كما أنني لا أضمن...
that she won't try to come after my mom again.
أن لا تؤذي أمي مجدداً
I told her to go to you and beg for your forgiveness.
أخبرتها أن تستجدي عفوك
But that's what she had been up to.
ولكن هذا ما تعمدت فعله
By the way, what do you plan to do after getting Lee Mi Kyung?
ماذا تنوي أن تفعل بعد القبض على (لي مي كيونغ)؟
I'll make her face Chairman Bae first.
سأجعلها أولاً تواجه رئيس مجلس الإدارة (باي)
That woman is someone who wants Chairman Bae's money, power,
فهي تريد الحصول على مال وسلطة رئيس المجلس (باي)
and even his heart.
وحتى على قلبه
So if she gets out of his shadow, she will lose everything.
لذا إن كُشفت إلى العلن، ستفقد كل شيء
I'm going to bring her in front of Chairman Bae...
سأحضرها إلى رئيس المجلس (باي)...
to reveal everything and have her completely thrown out.
لأكشف كل شيء، وأتخلص منها تماماً
So that she may never approach Mother and Song Yi Heon.
كي لا تقترب من أمي ومن (سونغ يي هيون)
We will bring her no matter what. Don't worry.
سنحضرها مهما كلف الأمر، لا تقلق
Then I will trust you...
إذاً سأثق بك...
and care for Mother...
وأهتم بوالدتي...
while focusing on midterms.
وأركز على الامتحان النصفي
"Midterms?"
"الامتحان النصفي؟"
This test...
هذا الاختبار...
will be the first test to be reflected in his records.
سيكون الأول الذي ستنعكس نتائجه عليه
It's the test that decides whether he can go to college or not.
الاختبار الذي سيحدد إمكانية دخوله إلى الجامعة
So whether I end up in juvenile hall or not,
سواء دخلت سجن الأحداث أم لا
and whether I go to college or not both depend on you.
أو كسبت الجامعة أم لا هذان الأمران يعتمدان عليك
- Please do your best. - Yes, Boss.
- افعل جهدك رجاءً - حسناً أيها القائد
- Good luck. - Yes, sir.
- حظاً موفقاً - نعم أيها القائد
Take care, Boss.
كن حذراً يا سيدي
I heard you were fired from the hair salon.
سمعت أنك طُردت من صالون الحلاقة
Where are you going, when you have no place to sleep?
أين تذهبين وليس لديك مكان تنامين فيه؟
I wasn't fired, I just quit.
لم أُطرد، بل استقلت
And what would I do here? It doesn't even feel like home.
وماذا أفعل هنا؟ لا أشعر بأنه منزلي
Why, you...
لمَ! أنت...
If it's not home, then what is it?
إن لم يكن منزلاً، فما هو؟
You don't even come home often,
إنك لا تأتي إلى المنزل حتى
so why are you going nuts?
لمَ تفقد عقلك؟
What did you call me?
ماذا دعوتني؟
And "nuts"? To your brother?
"مجنون"؟ تقولينها لأخيك؟
I already have a headache. Why are you acting out as well?
إنني أشعر بالصداع، لمَ تثيرين المشكلات أيضاً؟
Dad said to give this to you.
أخبرني والدي أن أعطيك هذا
(Prepare For Tomorrow Savings Account Bankbook)
"حساب المدخرات البنكي استعداداً للغد"
They cut off the water.
قُطعت المياه
How is this a home when you can't even shower?
كيف يكون هذا منزلاً إن لم تستطع الاستحمام؟
What did you just say?
ماذا قلتِ تواً؟
Come here, you. Hey!
تعالي إلى هنا، يا هذه!
That little...
تلك...
Don't even think about testifying or anything like that.
"لا تفكر حتى أن تشهد أو شيء من هذا القبيل"
If you do, you'll end up going to juvie.
"إن فعلت ستدخل إلى سجن الأحداث"
Crazy. Why would I go to juvie?
ما هذا الجنون! لمَ سأدخل إلى سجن الأحداث؟
Whatever.
لا يهم
Lawsuit or testifying, I'm going to ignore it all.
سأتجاهل الأمر، سواء كانت شكوى أم شهادة
Besides, when he reports us, your name is bound to come up.
"كما أنه إن أبلغ عنا سيذكر اسمك بالتأكيد"
Do you think he won't name you...
"أتظن أنه لن يقول اسمك..."
because you didn't report him?
"لأنك لم تبلغ عنه"
You started this whole thing.
"أنت بدأت الأمر كله"
He won't say my name during the investigation, will he?
لن يقول اسمي خلال التحقيق، أليس كذلك؟
Should I ask him not to say it?
هل أطلب منه ألا يذكره؟
(Prepare For Tomorrow Savings Account Bankbook)
"دفتر حساب المدخرات البنكي استعداداً للغد"
I can somehow manage to solve probability problems.
يمكنني تدبر حل المشكلات الاحتمالية
But I really can't understand functions.
ولكنني لا أتمكن من فهم الدالات
Watch.
انظر
For this problem...
لهذه المشكلة...
You got it wrong here.
فهمتها بشكل خاطئ هنا
You have to substitute it here.
عليك استبدالها هنا
Do you mean I could be a substitute teacher?
هل تعني أنه يمكنني أن أكون مدرساً بديلاً؟
I'm not even done with these problems.
لم أنتهِ من هذه المشكلات بعد
No, you need to substitute this, not the other one.
عليك استبدال هذه، وليس الأخرى
They cancelled the school violence committee.
لقد ألغوا مجلس مكافحة العنف المدرسي
I saw it.
رأيت هذا
Did your father sign the cancellation request?
هل وقع والدك على طلب الإلغاء؟
You have a lot of problems on your hands,
لديك الكثير من الأعباء
with the lawsuit and your mother.
بما فيها القضية ووالدتك
I wanted to handle at least the committee for you.
أردت أن أتصرف فيما يخص مجلس المكافحة من أجلك
Are you sure it wasn't because you wanted to make me study...
أأنت متيقن أنه لم يكن من أجل أن أدرس...
so that you can see Song Yi Heon earlier?
كي ترى (سونغ يي هيون) بوقت أبكر؟
There's also that, but...
وهذا أيضاً سبب، ولكن...
I didn't want to lose a friend.
لم أرد أن أفقد صديقاً
You're the only real friend I have.
أنت صديقي الحقيقي الوحيد
So you can't ever go to juvie.
لذا لا يمكنك الذهاب إلى سجن الأحداث
Fine.
حسناً
Make sure to say the same even when Song Yi Heon returns.
تأكد من قول الأمر نفسه عند عودة (سونغ يي هيون)
That you're friends.
أنكما صديقان
I'm sure I told you that I won't wait for long.
"لن أنتظر كثيراً، متيقناً أنني أخبرتك بهذا"
(I'm sure I told you that I won't wait for long. Yi Heon)
"لن أنتظر كثيراً، متيقناً أنني أخبرتك بهذا إلى (يي هيون)"
I'm sure you heard that we have an advantage.
مؤكد أنك سمعت أن لدينا الأفضلية
We decided not to drop it.
قررنا عدم التنازل عن القضية
Was it, "I'll take charge as if I were galloping on a tiger?"
ألم تقل "سأتحمل النتائج بكل قوة وجرأة"؟
We will charge like that as well, so let's take this until the end.
وهكذا سنبلغ عنك، وسنكمل الأمر للنهاية
They will only come to their senses once they fall off the tiger.
سيعودون إلى صوابهم عندما يخفقون
Those unethical kids...
هؤلاء الأولاد معدومو الأخلاق...
(Jong Cheol)
"(جونغ تشيول)"
This is best for waking up.
هذا جيد للتركيز
Boss Chil Sung showed up.
ظهر (تشيل سونغ) يا سيدي
He met the retired bosses at an inn in Gangneung...
قابل الزعماء المتقاعدين في فندق (غانغنيونغ)...
and said that he would visit soon after asking about us.
وقال إنه سيزورنا قريباً بعد أن يسأل عنا
It's a relief to hear that...
كم هو مريح سماع هذا...
he's doing well.
هو بخير
He heard about his nephew, so he will be here soon.
سمع عن ابن أخيه، لذا سيأتي قريباً
What about Chairman Bae and Lee Mi Kyung?
ماذا عن رئيس المجلس (باي) و(لي مي كيونغ)؟
We kept an eye on them these past few days,
راقبناهما خلال الأيام الماضية
but there's no sign of Lee Mi Kyung and Chairman Bae at the office.
ولكن لا أثر لـ (لي مي كيونغ) أو رئيس المجلس (باي) في مكتبه
It seems like...
يبدو أن...
the appellants have no intentions of dropping it.
المشتكين لا يرغبون في التنازل
Then if we don't find Lee Mi Kyung, will you become the assailant?
إذاً إن لم نجد (لي مي كيونغ)، ستكون أن المعتدي؟
We will do whatever it takes to find where Lee Mi Kyung is.
سنبذل جهدنا لنجد مكان (لي مي كيونغ)
You can't ever go to juvie.
لا يمكنك الذهاب إلى سجن الأحداث قط
Right.
صحيح
It may be hard, but you just focus on your exams.
ركز في امتحاناتك، رغم صعوبة الأمر
Good luck.
حظاً موفقاً
Number 16, 5. Number 17, 1.
الرقم ستة عشر، خمسة الرقم سبعة عشر، واحد
Number 18, 1.
الرقم ثمانية عشر، واحد
Number 19, 4.
الرقم تسعة عشر، أربعة
Number 20, 5.
الرقم عشرون، خمسة
That's it.
انتهى
You got everything on the last page, Song Yi Heon?
كتبت حتى وصلت إلى الصفحة الأخيرة يا (سونغ يي هيون)
- What? - Goodness.
- ماذا؟ - عجباً
- Really? - The questions were really hard.
- حقاً؟ - كانت الأسئلة صعبة جداً
- Amazing. - Gosh.
- هذا رائع - عجباً
President, we're done marking them, right?
أيها الرئيس، هل أنهينا الإشارة إليهم؟
What? Yes.
ماذا؟ نعم
Take your phones, and we don't have an assembly today,
خذوا هواتفكم، ولن تُكلفوا بالوظائف اليوم
so you can all go home except for those on cleaning duty.
يمكنكم الذهاب إلى منازلكم باستثناء مَن لديهم واجب التنظيف
Good job on your exams.
حظاً موفقاً في امتحاناتكم
Here.
تفضل
Go on and tell him.
اذهبي وأخبريه
(Detective Min, The case has been sent to the prosecution.)
"المحقق (مين)، أُرسلت القضية إلى النيابة العامة"
(And your father is abroad at the moment.)
"ووالدك خارج البلاد حالياً"
Gosh...
عجباً...
Yi Heon.
(يي هيون)
Do you want to go and have tteokbokki with me?
هل تريد الخروج معي لتناول طبق من الأرز الطري
Sorry, I have to go somewhere today.
أنا متأسف، لدي عمل لأقوم به اليوم
Yi Heon.
(يي هيون)
What? You go to my school?
ماذا؟ هل ترتادين المدرسة نفسها؟
What are you doing, since exams are over?
ماذا تفعل، بما أن الامتحانات انتهت؟
I have something to tell you.
لدي شيء أخبرك به
Do you want to go and eat tteokbokki?
هل تريد الذهاب لتناول طبق من الأرز الطري؟
Sorry, there's something I have to do.
أنا متأسف، علي القيام بشيء ما
Instead, I will buy tteokbokki and tea next time.
على العكس، سأدعوك إلى طبق الأرز والشاي في المرة القادمة
What do you say we talk then?
ما رأيك أن نتكلم حينئذ؟
Okay. For sure.
حسناً، بالتأكيد
She's...
هي...
Hey...
يا هذه...
Song Yi Heon! What was that?
ما كان هذا يا (سونغ يي هيون)؟
Why would Choi Seol Hee eat tteokbokki with you?
لمَ قد تتناول (تشوي سيؤول هيي) الأرز الطري معك؟
What will you talk about?
ما الذي سوف تتحدثان به؟
- How do you know him? - Choi Seol Hee.
- كيف تعرفها؟ - (تشوي سيؤول هيي)
She wins medals at the National Sports Festival,
تكسب الأوسمة في مهرجان الرياضة الوطني
and she's on the archery national team.
وهي في فريق الرماية الوطني
She's so famous.
إنها مشهورة جداً
Are you having a fling with Choi Seol Hee?
هل تتواعدان؟
No, it's not like that.
لا، ليس كذلك
I just saw her a few times at the study room. That's all.
رأيتها بضع مرات في غرفة الدراسة هذا هو الأمر
Is she prettier, or am I?
هل هي أجمل أو أنا؟
What?
ماذا؟
Both of you are pretty, of course.
كلتاكما جميلتان بالطبع
But maybe it's because Seol Hee has a small face,
ولكن ربما لأن (سيؤول هيي) تملك وجهاً أصغر
she seems to have good proportions.
يبدو أنها تملك ملامح جميلة
So you're saying...
هل تقول إذاً...
I have a big face?
إنني أملك وجهاً كبيراً؟
No, I...
لا، أنا...
"You don't have a big face."
"لا تملكين وجهاً كبيراً"
No, I don't like small faces.
لا، لا تعجبي الوجوه الصغيرة
You have to have a big face...
عليك الحصول على وجه كبير...
to have big eyes, nose, and mouth, which looks cool.
ليكون لديك عينان كبيرتان وأنف وفم، وهذا جميل
So you're saying my face is big.
إذاً تقول إن وجهي كبير
No, I mean...
لا، أعني...
Your face isn't big.
وجهك ليس كبيراً
It's just that Seol Hee has an exceptionally small face.
ولكن (سيؤول هيي) تملك وجهاً صغيراً بشكل استثنائي
You're so annoying!
أنت مزعج جداً
Min Ji!
(مين جي)!
You don't know anything about women.
أنت لا تعرف أي شيء عن النساء
Hey, Nam Min Ji!
يا (نام مين جي)!
Why is it even more difficult...
لمَ الأمر يبدو أصعب...
to figure out ladies' hearts than solving problems?
عندما يتعلق بقلوب النساء من حل المشكلات؟
Do you also have something with Min Ji?
هل بينك وبين (مين جاي) شيء ما أيضاً؟
Are you two-timing them?
هل تواعد الاثنتين؟
No. I have something important, so I should go.
لا، لدي شيء مهم لذا علي الذهاب
Where are you going? You need to follow Nam Min Ji.
أين تذهب؟ عليك اللحاق بـ (نام مين جي)
You can't go like that even if you don't know women!
لا يمكنك الذهاب هكذا حتى وإن لم تفهم النساء!
You'll ruin your school life!
ستدمر حياتك المدرسية!
Hey!
يا هذا!
For cases involving minors, we contact the guardians first.
في قضايا القاصرين نتواصل مع أوليائهم أولاً
But OK Construction won't give us Chairman Bae's personal number,
ولكن شركة (أو كي) لم تعطنا رقم رئيس المجلس (باي)
he won't go to work at all,
لم يذهب إلى عمله أبداً
and it didn't seem like he was at home,
ولا يبدو أنه في المنزل
so we checked just in case,
لذا تحققنا بالأمر تحسباً
and we found a departure record.
ووجدنا بطاقة مغادرة
But...
لكن...
How did this get turned over to the prosecution so quickly?
كيف تحولت القضية إلى النيابة العامة بهذه السرعة؟
I'm baffled as well.
أنا مصدوم أيضاً
The prosecution suddenly contacted us in the morning,
تواصلت معنا النيابة العامة فجأة هذا الصباح
saying they will handle it quickly.
قائلين إنهم سيتولون القضية بسرعة
They said they would investigate as soon as possible,
قالوا إنهم سيحققون بالأمر حالما يستطيعون
so you should better prepare in advance.
لذا ينبغي أن تتحضر سلفاً
The assailant and victim's claims are completely different,
ادعاءات المعتدي والضحية مختلفان تماماً
so the investigation will be a three-party encounter.
لذا فالتحقيق سيكون ثلاثي الأطراف
(Your criminal mediation schedule will be held on May 8, 2023.)
"سيُعقد جدول الوساطة الجنائية في ثمانية مايو ألفين وثلاثة وعشرين"
(Please attend at the Seoul Central District Prosecutor's Office.)
"الرجاء الحضور إلى مكتب النيابة العامة في مقاطعة (سيؤول)"
It says...
الرسالة تقول...
to come next Monday.
أن أحضر الإثنين القادم
It's right after this weekend?
مباشرة بعد عطلة نهاية الأسبوع
There are many victims,
هناك العديد من الضحايا
and the violence is quite severe,
والعنف شديد جداً
but it isn't something to be processed this quickly.
ولكنه ليس أمراً يعالج بهذه السرعة
If this goes on,
إن استمر الأمر هكذا
then the assailant will be taken in right after the investigation.
سيُقبض على المعتدي مباشرة بعد التحقيق
Then if I become the assailant,
إذاً إن أُثبت أنني المعتدي
I guess I won't be able to attend school.
أعتقد أنني لن أستطيع ارتياد المدرسة
I think someone who is very interested in this case...
أعتقد أن أحداً يهتم جداً بهذه القضية...
is influencing the prosecution.
يؤثر في النيابة العامة
(School Violence Committee Cancellation Request, Guardian)
"طلب إلغاء مجلس مكافحة العنف المدرسي، الوصي"
My Se Kyung turned this in?
رفض السيد (سي كيونغ) هذا؟
Yes.
نعم
Still, how can you cancel it without additional confirmation?
مع هذا، كيف تلغونها من دون تأكيد إضافي؟
Who would trust the school to handle work?
مَن سيثق بأعمال هذه المدرسة؟
Sir...
سيدي...
Don't get too upset.
لا تغضب
Ma'am, what do I do with the extra...
ماذا سأفعل يا سيدتي بـ...
Did you turn in the cancellation form?
هل سلمت طلب الإلغاء؟
After getting it signed by your mother?
بعد أن وقعتها من والدتك؟
I didn't think you would do it.
لم أعتقد أنك ستفعل هذا
Regarding Song Yi Heon's charges for school violence,
نظراً لاتهام (سونغ يي هيون) بالعنف المدرسي
I told them to hand it over to the prosecutor's office.
أخبرتهم أن يسلموا القضية إلى مكتب النيابة العامة
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
I already told the local precinct.
أخبرت بالفعل مركز الشرطة المحلي
I told them to tell me first...
أن يخبروني أولاً...
if they receive any case related to Song Yi Heon.
إن استلموا قضية تخص (سونغ يي هيون)
When I heard that the meeting was cancelled,
عندما علمت أن اللقاء قد ألغي
I handed it over.
سلمتهم إياها
Yi Heon didn't do that.
لم يفعل (يي هيون) هذا
- Yi Heon is the victim. - Wake up!
- إن (يي هيون) هو الضحية - كن متنبهاً أكثر!
I can't even handle the fact that he coaxed my son...
لا أستطيع أن أتحمل خداعه لابني...
and led him astray,
ومساعدته له ليضل طريقه
but he's the kind that cancels the meeting behind my back...
ولكنه قد خدعني وألغى الاجتماع...
and says for himself that he's a gangster,
ويقول عن نفسه إنه عضو في عصابة
and he's a scum that hits other kids.
وحثالة يضرب أولاداً آخرين
If the school can't, he should be punished through legislation.
إن لم تستطع المدرسة معاقبته فالقانون سيفعل
I'll do everything I can to send him to juvie...
سأفعل ما أستطيع عليه لإرساله إلى سجن الأحداث...
as soon as possible,
بأسرع ما يمكن
so that he may never set foot in school again.
حتى لا يدخل إلى المدرسة مجدداً
Watch what you say, please.
انتبه لكلامك أرجوك
I'm the one who cancelled the meeting.
لستُ مَن ألغى الاجتماع
Because I'm not a victim.
لأنني لست ضحية
Are you...
هل أنت...
even the Se Kyung I know?
(سي كيونغ) الذي أعرفه؟
I'm doing my best...
أنا أفعل ما بوسعي...
to raise you properly.
لأنشئك على نحو ملائم
Why are you breaking down like this?
لمَ تتمرد بهذه الطريقة؟
Are you by any chance...
هل تفكر بأي شكل كان...
thinking about testifying?
أن تشهد؟
If you do testify,
إن شهدت بالفعل
don't think of ever seeing me again.
لا تفكر أبداً برؤيتي مجدداً
You won't be my son.
لن تكون ابني
(Hello. This is the Seoul District Public Prosecutors' Office.)
"مرحباً، مكتب النيابة العامة في مقاطعة (سيؤول)"
(Your criminal mediation schedule will be held on May 8, 2023.)
"سيُعقد جدول الوساطة الجنائية في ثمانية مايو ألفين وثلاثة وعشرين"
(Please attend at the Seoul Central District Prosecutor's Office.)
"الرجاء الحضور إلى مكتب النيابة العامة في مقاطعة (سيؤول)"
It's not Lee Mi Kyung.
ليست (لي مي كيونغ)
If it was Lee Mi Kyung, she would have already reported it.
إن كانت (لي مي كيونغ) لكانت أبلغت بالفعل
She wouldn't wait for weeks.
لم تكن لتنتظر أسابيع عدة
Someone who would suddenly report it to the prosecution...
إنه شخص أبلغ النيابة العامة فجأة...
and handle the work this fast...
وتولى الأمر على نحو سريع...
I'll do everything I can to send him to juvie...
"سأفعل ما بوسعي لإرساله إلى سجن الأحداث..."
as soon as possible,
"بأسرع وقت"
so that he may never set foot in school again.
"كي لا يدخل إلى المدرسة مجدداً أبداً"
Make sure to say the same even when Song Yi Heon returns.
"تأكد من قول الشيء نفسه عند عودة (سونغ يي هيون)"
That you're friends.
"أنكما صديقان"
Why were you looking at Yi Heon these past few days?
لمَ تسترق النظر إلى (يي هيون) في الأيام الماضية؟
Are you going to sue him, along with Jang Byung Chul and Park Duk Jun?
هل ستقاضيه كما فعل (جانغ بيونغ تشول) و(بارك دوك جون)؟
No way.
لا يمكن
I'm ignoring the calls from those guys.
أنا أتجاهل اتصالاتهم
Then what is it?
إذاً ما الأمر؟
Are you going to get information from Yi Heon and give it to them?
هل ستحصل على معلومات من (يي هيون) وتعطيها لهم؟
Who the witness is, and whether he has testimony?
مَن يكون الشاهد؟ وهل سيشهد؟
No, that's not it.
لا، ليس هذا هو الأمر
I just want to graduate quietly.
أريد أن أتخرج بهدوء فقط
Yi Heon will go to the juvie,
سيدخل (يي هيون) إلى سجن الأحداث
and you want to graduate, jerk?
وتريد التخرج أيها الأحمق؟
At first, I only teased Song Yi Heon...
في البداية، ضايقت (سونغ يي هيون)...
because he was all dark,
لأنه كان غامضاً
and I only wanted him to buy alcohol...
وأردته فقط أن يشتري المشروب...
and cigarettes since he was rich.
والسجائر لأنه كان ثرياً
I don't know how it came this far.
لا أعلم كيف تماديت بالأمر
How am I supposed to fix this?
كيف أستطيع إصلاح الأمر؟
I'll give you the solution.
سأعطيك الحل
You, Jang Byung Chul, and Park Duk Jun...
أنت و(جانغ بيونغ تشول) و(بارك دوك جون)...
have the video in your phones, right?
لديكم المقطع المصور في هواتفكم، أليس كذلك؟
The proof where we hit and harassed Yi Heon?
الذي يُثبت أننا ضربنا واعتدينا على (يي هيون)؟
Yi Heon told you to delete it, but I'm sure you didn't.
أخبركم (يي هيون) أن تمحوه ولكنني متيقن أنكم لم تفعلوا
Do whatever it takes, whether it's stealing their phones...
افعل ما بوسعك سواءً بسرقة هواتفهم...
or hacking their cloud storage, to gather them all...
أم اختراق الذاكرة الاحتياطية لتجمع المقاطع...
and reveal them at the investigation.
وتُظهرهم خلال التحقيق
You, Jang Byung Chul, Park Duk Jun, and all the other guys.
أنت و(جانغ بيونغ تشول) و(بارك دوك جون) والآخرون
That they are the real assailants and that Yi Heon was sued...
أنهم المعتدون الحقيقيون وأن (يي هيون) سيُحاكم...
when he was the victim.
على حين أنه الضحية
And also search all the CCTVs...
كما عليك أن تبحث في أجهزة المراقبة جميعها
to reveal that Yi Heon is the victim, understand?
لتكشف أن (يي هيون) هو الضحية، هل فهمت؟
That's the solution? Then what about me?
هذا هو الحل؟ وماذا عني؟
I won't be able to attend school and go to juvie.
لن أتمكن من حضور المدرسة وسأدخل سجن الأحداث
My father handed this case over to the prosecution, you fool.
لقد سلم والدي القضية إلى النيابة العامة يا أحمق
If we can't testify that Yi Heon is the victim,
إن لم نشهد أن (يي هيون) هو الضحية
Yi Heon will be arrested and sent to juvie...
سيُقبض على (يي هيون) ويُرسل إلى سجن الأحداث...
when he is innocent.
وهو بريء
I don't want to.
لا أريد هذا
Yi Heon even forgave you when you tried to kidnap his mother.
لقد سامحك (يي هيون) حتى عندما حاولت خطف والدته
He didn't even have the school violence committee held...
لم يقبل انعقاد مجلس مكافحة العنف المدرسي...
because he didn't want you to get expelled.
لأنه لم يردك أن تُطرد
Do you think Yi Heon doesn't know that the tables will be turned...
ألا تعتقد أن (يي هيون) يعلم أن الأمور ستختلف...
if you say that you're the assailant?
إذا قلتم إنكم المعتدون؟
He isn't saying anything to you when he knows everything.
لم يواجهك بأي شيء، رغم معرفته بالحقيقة
He's protecting you so you can attend school.
هو يحميك لتتمكن من ارتياد المدرسة
You choose.
اختر بنفسك
Will you neglect it like a coward, or...
هل ستتجاهل الأمر كالجبناء، أو...
Will you testify, like Yi Heon did,
هل ستشهد كما فعل (يي هيون)
and help him out?
وتساعده؟
I'm not doing anything.
لن أفعل أي شيء
It has nothing to do with me.
لا دخل لي بالأمر
Do you think Yi Heon doesn't know that the tables will be turned...
"ألا تظن أن (يي هيون) يعلم أن الأمور ستختلف..."
if you say that you're the assailant?
"إذا قلتم إنكم المعتدون؟"
He isn't saying anything to you when he knows everything.
"لم يواجهك بأي شيء، رغم معرفته بالحقيقة"
He's protecting you so you can attend school.
"هو يحميك لتتمكن من ارتياد المدرسة"
Why did he have to say that nonsense?
لمَ قلت هذا الهراء؟
(Byung Chul)
"(بيونغ تشول)"
Why won't you pick up?
لمَ لا تجيب؟
- You came? - What are you going to do?
- أتيت! - ماذا ستفعل؟
I'm not suing him.
لن أقاضيه
Are you really on Yi Heon's side now?
هل أنت حقاً تدعم (يي هيون)؟
Are you going to testify or something?
هل ستشهد لصالحه أم ماذا؟
And what if I do?
وماذا إن فعلت هذا؟
Then we're all dead.
إذاً ستقضي علينا جميعاً
No, I mean...
لا، أعني...
If you testify that we're the assailants,
إن شهدت أننا المعتدون...
I'm saying that we can't just stay still.
دعني أخبرك أن الأمر لن يمر مرور الكرام
We have no choice...
لا خيار لدينا...
but to say that you made us do it, and that you led it.
سوى القول إنك أجبرتنا على هذا، وكنت قائدنا
You and I are both dead.
سيُقضى علينا نحن الاثنان
Is that a threat?
هل هذا تهديد؟
No, I mean...
لا، أعني...
- So let's sue him together. - Forget it.
- لنقاضيه معاً - انسَ الأمر
I'm not going to do anything. That's that.
لن أفعل أي شيء، هذا هو الأمر
Hey, Jae Min.
اسمع يا (جاي مين)
Darn it.
سحقاً!
Why isn't he teaming up with us?
لمَ لا يتعاون معنا؟
Se Kyung told me...
أخبرني (سي كيونغ)...
his father transferred your case to the prosecution.
أن والده حوّل قضيتك إلى النيابة العامة
It must have been tough...
لا بد أن الأمر كان صعباً...
- for Se Kyung. - But...
- على (سي كيونغ) - لكنني...
I'm not going to come forward.
لن أفعل شيئاً
I never asked you to.
لم أطلب منك هذا
Why aren't you...
لمَ لا...
asking me to do so?
تطلب مني هذا؟
If I testify, you won't go to juvie,
إن شهدت لصالحك لن تدخل سجن الأحداث
and Byung Chul and Duk Jun will get arrested.
وسيُعتقل كل من (بيونغ تشول) و(دوك جون)
I heard my testimony is your only way out.
سمعت أن شهادتي هي طريقك الوحيد
Why aren't you asking for it, then?
لمَ لا تطلبها إذاً؟
You have no other choice.
لا تملك خياراً آخر
Are you going to go to juvie, then?
هل ستدخل سجن الأحداث إذاً؟
My father opened an instalment savings account.
فتح لي والدي حساباً للتوفير
Prepare for Tomorrow Instalment Savings.
دفتر حساب المدخرات استعداداً للغد
It's my college tuition.
إنها رسوم تسجيلي الجامعي
Yes.
نعم
I know I might not get into college with my grades.
لن أتمكن من دخول الجامعة بهذه الدرجات
But I should at least graduate high school...
ولكن عليّ التخرج من الثانوية على الأقل...
if I want to go to college.
إن أردت الالتحاق بالجامعة
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
But I'm so scared.
لكنني خائف جداً
You won't go to juvie.
لن تذهب إلى سجن الأحداث
A real adult...
الراشد الحقيقي...
helps the kids so they won't be miserable.
يساعد الشباب كي لا يكونوا مستائين
That's what an adult should do.
هذا ما يفعله الناضجون
Also, you apologized to the wrong person.
ثم أنك اعتذرت من الشخص الخاطئ
When the real Yi Heon comes back,
عندما يعود (يي هيون) الحقيقي
apologize to him...
اعتذر منه...
on your knees.
راكعاً على ركبتيك
Have you eaten?
هل تناولت الطعام؟
Mother is in the hospital because she is ill.
أمي في المستشفى لأنها مريضة
The housekeeper is staying with her at the hospital,
ستبقى مدبرة المنزل معها الليلة
so this is all I've got.
لذا هذا فقط ما لدي
This rice is freaking hot.
هذا الرز ساخن جداً
Do you want to get yelled at until you explode?
هل تريد أن أوبخك بشدة؟
Just eat what you have.
تناول من الموجود فقط
Some say people don't change.
البعض يقول لا أحد يتغير
But I believe you'll be able to change.
لكنني أؤمن أنك ستتمكن من التغير
So show me how different you can be.
لذا أرني كيف ستتغير
Just like now, don't bully others.
ثم أنت الآن، لا تتنمر على الآخرين
Don's skip school.
لا تتغيب عن المدرسة
And try to study hard.
وحاول الدراسة بجد
As I told you many times,
كما أخبرتك مرات عدة
you have to graduate high school to function...
عليك التخرج من الثانوية لتكون فاعلاً...
as a human being.
كإنسان
Stop lecturing me.
توقف عن وعظي
You'd be the high school dropout if you get arrested.
ستصبح مَن ترك الثانوية بعد أن تُعتقل
I mean...
أعني...
You're ruining dinner.
إنك تفسد العشاء
Why are you lecturing me when my parents wouldn't?
لمَ تقدم لي المواعظ التي لم يقدمها والديّ؟
My tongue slipped because of you.
لقد سال لعابي بسببك
You don't have to send me off.
ليس عليك أن ترافقني
I'm on my way to visit my mother in the hospital.
أنا في طريقي لزيارة أمي في المستشفى
Hey.
يا هذا
Why did you invite me for dinner?
لمَ دعوتني إلى العشاء؟
It was because...
لأنك...
you looked hungry.
بدوت جائعاً
Jae Min.
(جاي مين)
Do you know what is the thing...
أتعلم ما هو الشيء الذي...
you can't have more even if you want more?
لا يمكنك الاستزادة منه ولو رغبت في ذلك؟
And the thing you want to stop, but it won't?
والذي تريد إيقافه، لكنك لا تستطيع؟
It's time.
إنه الوقت
So, study when you still can.
لذا ادرس طالما تستطيع
You should go to college, right?
عليك الالتحاق بالجامعة، اتفقنا؟
You said I could just graduate high school.
قلت إن علي التخرج من الثانوية فقط
Are you an old fart or what?
هل أنت أحمق أو ماذا؟
I get that a lot.
أسمع هذا كثيراً
Get home safe.
مع السلامة
(Hong Jae Min started calling me a stalker.)
"بدأ (هونغ جاي مين) بدعوتي المتعقب"
(I hate school. I'm tired of this.)
"أكره المدرسة، لقد تعبت من هذا كله"
(I want to quit. I want to die.)
"أريد الانسحاب، أريد الموت"
(Will I be able to be friends with anyone?)
"هل سأتمكن من تكوين صداقة مع أحد ما؟"
(I don't know what it is to share the same feelings.)
"لا أعلم ما هي مشاركة المشاعر"
(In the end, even my friends will abandon me.)
"في نهاية المطاف، سيتخلى عني أصدقائي أيضاً"
(To Se Kyung: "Pure EHC." Read it backward.)
"إلى (سي كيونغ): (لأ افت) اقرأها عكسياً"
"Pure EHC." Read it backward
"(لأ افت) اقرأها عكسياً"
(Yi Heon: "Pure EHC." Read it backward.)
"من (يي هيون): (لأ افت) اقرأها عكسياً"
Cheer up.
تفاءل!
I heard about your father.
سمعت ما فعله والدك
It's okay. It's not your fault.
لا بأس، ليس ذنبك
What about you? Are you doing okay?
ماذا عنك؟ هل أنت بخير؟
You'll be examined by the prosecution tomorrow.
ستذهب إلى النيابة العامة غداً
There were a few goals...
هناك بعض الأهداف...
I wanted to achieve before Yi Heon came back.
التي أردت تحقيقها قبل عودة (يي هيون)
Escape school violence.
التخلص من العنف المدرسي
Protect Mother.
حماية الوالدة
Get into university. And, make friends.
الالتحاق بالجامعة، وأيضاً تكوين صداقات
I failed to achieve anything,
أخفقت في تحقيق الأهداف كلها
but I made one friend at least.
ولكن كسبت صديقاً واحداً على الأقل
So I'm glad.
لذا أنا ممتن
What do you mean? You can still achieve all your goals.
ماذا تعني؟ ما زال بإمكانك تحقيق أهدافك
I'll testify.
سأشهد
Come to think of it,
عندما فكرت بالأمر
I saw Yi Heon getting bullied many times.
فقد رأيت (يي هيون) يتعرض للتنمر مرات عديدة
Move over. I'll show it to you.
"تنحّ جانباً، سأريك إياها"
- I didn't get to go. - Move over.
- "لم أتمكن من التصويب" - "تنحّ جانباً"
- I didn't get to do it. - Okay.
- "لم أتمكن من فعلها" - "حسناً"
I knew you'd be good at it.
"كنت أعلم أنك جيد بهذا"
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I'm going to protect you.
سأحميك
For some reason,
لسبب ما
my father's threats didn't hurt as much and were bearable.
لم تؤثر بي تهديدات والدي وتحملتها
It's all thanks to you.
هذا كله بفضلك
I'm going to return your favour.
سأرد إليك المعروف
Don't push yourself too hard.
لا تضغط على نفسك كثيراً
It's grownups' job to solve a difficult problem.
حل المشكلات الصعبة يخص الراشدين
Also, as you know, Yi Heon is innocent.
كما تعلم، فإن (يي هيون) بريء
"A friend."
"صديق"
"A friend." I like that.
"صديق" كهذا
What?
ماذا؟
You used to hang out with your friends all the time.
اعتدت أن تتسكع مع أصدقائك دائماً
Why do you come here so often these days?
لمَ تأتي إلى هنا كثيراً هذه الأيام؟
I have no place to sleep over, so I'm going to sleep here.
لا أملك مكاناً للنوم، لذا سأنام هنا اليوم
What about the water? Did you get it back?
ماذا عن الماء؟ هل استعدتها؟
Some say people don't change.
"البعض يقول لا أحد يتغير"
But I believe you'll be able to change.
"لكنني أثق أنك ستتمكن من التغير"
So, show me how different you can be.
"لذا أرني كم ستتغير"
Darn it.
سحقاً
Why the heck are you crying? It's annoying.
لمَ تبكي بحق السماء؟ هذا مزعج
You're up.
لقد استيقظتِ
Yes.
نعم
You look good today.
تبدين بخير اليوم
Do you want some water?
هل تريدين بعض الماء؟
Well... I might...
في الواقع... قد...
have to go out today.
يكون عليَّ الخروج اليوم
It won't take long.
لن أتأخر
Focus on getting better until I come back.
ركزي على التحسن إلى أن أعود
Is there a girl you have a crush on?
هل هناك فتاة أنت معجب بها؟
You're more built now.
أصبحت أكثر قوة الآن
A man gets fitter when he likes someone.
يصبح الشاب أكثر رشاقة عندما يُعجب بأحد
Your father was like that too.
كان والدك هكذا أيضاً
He started playing golf and going to the gym after seeing that witch.
بدأ بلعب الغولف والذهاب إلى النادي بعد رؤية تلك الساحرة
"That witch?"
"تلك الساحرة؟"
That witch, Lee Mi Kyung.
الشريرة (لي مي كيونغ)
Recently, he even bought her an apartment to live in.
اشترى لها شقة لتسكن بها مؤخراً
But I don't know if she knows...
لكن لا أعلم إن كانت تعرف...
that it means to take it and bugger off.
أن معنى هذا "خذيها واغربي"
I'm sure he's seeing some other witch already.
أراهن أنه يواعد شريرة أخرى بالفعل
That's your father.
هكذا هو والدك
When was this?
متى كان هذا؟
Two years ago?
قبل سنتين؟
Do you know...
هل تعلمين...
where it is?
أين هي؟
It's Unit 2402, 1-dong, Hwi Castle Apartment, Jangpyeon-dong.
في الوحدة 2402، (واحد - دونغ) شقة (هوي كاسل)، (جانغبيون - دونغ)
That's Lee Mi Kyung's place. Go and get her.
هذا منزل (لي مي كيونغ) أحضروها
When Byung Chul and Duk Jun's clan sees that we got her,
عندما يرى (بيونغ تشول) و(دوك جون) أنها معنا
they'll get flustered, and the investigation will go sideways.
سيرتابون وسيغفلون التحقيقات
(Byung Chul)
"(بيونغ تشول)"
I'll do it. Where do I have to be?
سأفعل هذا، أين ينبغي أن أكون؟
When you're home, eat and take a shower.
عندما تأتي إلى المنزل تناول الطعام واستحم
Sleep at home from now on.
نم في منزلك من الآن فصاعداً
Darn it.
سحقاً
(Prosecution Service)
"مكتب النيابة العامة"
Open it.
افتحه
I really shouldn't.
لا ينبغي عليّ هذا حقاً
- This is housebreaking. - Open it.
- هذا يدعى اقتحام منزل - افتحه
If you don't open it, you'll be in trouble right away.
إن لم تفتحه ستواجه مشكلة فوراً
Open it! Move over.
افتحه! تنحّ جانباً
(Prosecution Service)
"مكتب النيابة العامة"
We got this.
سنكسب القضية
She's not here.
ليست هنا
It's indeed her place,
إنه بالتأكيد منزلها
but it looks like it has been vacant for a while.
لكن يبدو أنه خالٍ منذ مدة
Come on out.
هيا اخرج
- I'm not leaving. - Come.
- لن أغادر - تعال
I said I'm not leaving!
قلت إنني لن أغادر!
How dare you?
كيف تجرؤ؟
Aren't you supposed to be at school?
ألا ينبغي أن تكون في المدرسة؟
No. It's right for me to be here.
لا، بل الصحيح أن أكون هنا
I told you that I wouldn't mention your name.
قلت إنني لن أذكر اسمك
Couldn't you understand what I said?
ألم تفهم ما قلته؟
What the heck are you doing right now?
ما الذي تفعله هنا بحق السماء؟
Can't you tell?
ألا يمكنك أن تعرف؟
I'm stabbing in the back.
إنني أطعن في الظهر
When I see those punks,
"عندما أرى هؤلاء الحمقى"
I can see why guilty ones should get punished.
"أفهم لمَ على المذنبين أن يُعاقبوا"
And this way, I'll feel less unfortunate.
"وهكذا، لن أشعر بالحظ السيئ كثيراً"
Apologize.
"أعتذر"
Song Yi Heon...
"(سونغ يي هيون)..."
might be a victim of this case.
"قد يكون الضحية في هذه القضية"
But what he did to you makes him an assailant.
"ولكن ما فعله لك يجعله مجرماً"
Aren't you going to apologize to me?
"ألن تعتذر مني؟"
I wanted to, but I couldn't get the chance.
"أردت هذا، ولكن لم أحصل على فرصة"
I'm sorry about everything.
"أعتذر عن كل شيء"
I really want to be your friend too.
"أريد أن أكون صديقك أيضاً حقاً"
I'll think about it.
"سأفكر بالأمر"
And about Yi Heon,
"وبالنسبة لـ (يي هيون)"
- is he going to another school? - "Another school?"
- "هل سيذهب إلى مدرسة أخرى؟" - "مدرسة أخرى؟"
I didn't pay much attention back then,
"لم أنتبه كثيراً حينئذ"
but he told me to take care of you when he was gone.
"لكنه أخبرني أن أعتني بك عندما يذهب"